<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts on @brismuth&#39;s blog</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drafts on @brismuth&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a chrome extension to automate stuff</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-chrome-extension-to-automate-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-chrome-extension-to-automate-stuff/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Recently I was looking for a way to send bulk text messages via Google Voice. I’m not talking about MMS messages - those are terrible for large groups, and have reliability issues with fringe carriers and MVNOs.
I couldn’t find any way to do that, and I decided to write a chrome extension to automate it myself. I learned a few helpful things along the way, and thought I’d share them here.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a very cheap (but awesome) home server</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-very-cheap-but-awesome-home-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-very-cheap-but-awesome-home-server/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I’m paranoid when it comes to my data. On the other hand, I’m also very stingy! I want to spend as little money as possible and still have peace of mind
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending email through your gmail account from your Linux server</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__sending-email-through-your-gmail-account-from-your-linux-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__sending-email-through-your-gmail-account-from-your-linux-server/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          If you want to use a Gmail account as a free SMTP server on your Ubuntu-Linux server, you will find this article useful. This guide is tested with Ubuntu 12.04. If you face any issue, feel free to use the comments section below.
Relaying Postfix mails via smtp.gmail.com: First, install all necessary packages: sudo apt-get install postfix mailutils libsasl2-2 ca-certificates libsasl2-modules
If you do not have postfix installed before, postfix configuration wizard will ask you some questions.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The one book that every software developer should read</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__one-book-that-every-software-developer-should-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__one-book-that-every-software-developer-should-read/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          There are many books recommended for software developers. There’s an entire Stack Overflow thread dedicated to this topic and many blog posts as well. I’ve recently read Designing Data Intensive Applications, The Design of Everyday Things, and Don’t Make Me Think by Steve Krug. I learned many useful, applicable things from each of those.
However, there is one book above all others that I feel that all developers should read. It isn’t about building software, it’s about building relationships.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a non-Project Fi phone on Project Fi</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__using-a-nonproject-fi-phone-on-project-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__using-a-nonproject-fi-phone-on-project-fi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          nexus 5x bootloop
pixel expensive
honor 8
Voicemail notification failure; please contact Project Fi Support (1-844-TALK2FI) or call your number directly to hear the voicemail.
VM:CAIaLgosCihPVklXTVJKSldJT1pZS0xLWk1KTlVIWVRVS1dVUVVaT1hRWlRQT0dPEAIOPpA
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>