<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello Friend</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello Friend</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.brismuth.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a chrome extension to automate stuff</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-chrome-extension-to-automate-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-chrome-extension-to-automate-stuff/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Recently I was looking for a way to send bulk text messages via Google Voice. I’m not talking about MMS messages - those are terrible for large groups, and have reliability issues with fringe carriers and MVNOs.
I couldn’t find any way to do that, and I decided to write a chrome extension to automate it myself. I learned a few helpful things along the way, and thought I’d share them here.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a very cheap (but awesome) home server</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-very-cheap-but-awesome-home-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__how-to-build-a-very-cheap-but-awesome-home-server/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I’m paranoid when it comes to my data. On the other hand, I’m also very stingy! I want to spend as little money as possible and still have peace of mind
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sending email through your gmail account from your Linux server</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__sending-email-through-your-gmail-account-from-your-linux-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__sending-email-through-your-gmail-account-from-your-linux-server/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          If you want to use a Gmail account as a free SMTP server on your Ubuntu-Linux server, you will find this article useful. This guide is tested with Ubuntu 12.04. If you face any issue, feel free to use the comments section below.
Relaying Postfix mails via smtp.gmail.com: First, install all necessary packages: sudo apt-get install postfix mailutils libsasl2-2 ca-certificates libsasl2-modules
If you do not have postfix installed before, postfix configuration wizard will ask you some questions.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The one book that every software developer should read</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__one-book-that-every-software-developer-should-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__one-book-that-every-software-developer-should-read/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          There are many books recommended for software developers. There’s an entire Stack Overflow thread dedicated to this topic and many blog posts as well. I’ve recently read Designing Data Intensive Applications, The Design of Everyday Things, and Don’t Make Me Think by Steve Krug. I learned many useful, applicable things from each of those.
However, there is one book above all others that I feel that all developers should read. It isn’t about building software, it’s about building relationships.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a non-Project Fi phone on Project Fi</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__using-a-nonproject-fi-phone-on-project-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 16:10:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/drafts/draft__using-a-nonproject-fi-phone-on-project-fi/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          nexus 5x bootloop
pixel expensive
honor 8
Voicemail notification failure; please contact Project Fi Support (1-844-TALK2FI) or call your number directly to hear the voicemail.
VM:CAIaLgosCihPVklXTVJKSldJT1pZS0xLWk1KTlVIWVRVS1dVUVVaT1hRWlRQT0dPEAIOPpA
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Steam on a Chromebook</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/how-to-install-steam-on-a-chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 04:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/how-to-install-steam-on-a-chromebook/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          There are already numerous guides out there for installing Steam on Chromebooks with Crouton, but that requires putting your Chromebook into developer mode, which is not ideal.
However, in 2018 Google added native Linux app support to Chrome OS via project Crostini. This is a guide for installing Steam on a Chromebook via the native Linux app support.
Step 1: Check if your device is supported First, make sure that your device supports Linux apps.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Chrome OS’s native Samba client</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/how-to-use-chrome-oss-native-samba-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 07:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/how-to-use-chrome-oss-native-samba-client/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          As reported a few months ago, the engineers at Google have been working on adding native Samba support to the Chrome OS Files app. This is a guide for using this new feature, along with caveats.
Step 1: Enable the feature This feature is still in the experimental phase as of Chrome OS 68, so you’ll need to enable it. Navigate to chrome://flags/#native-smb in your browser and change the dropdown for “Native Smb Client” to “Enabled”.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to send bulk texts with Google voice</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/how-to-send-bulk-texts-with-google-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 01:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/how-to-send-bulk-texts-with-google-voice/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Sometimes you want to send a text message to a large group of people. MMS isn’t a great approach — you’d be starting a group chat with a bunch of people that may not even have each other’s contact info. Some people may be annoyed if you do that, especially if others start chatting in the thread. If you ever need to add someone or remove someone from the group your only option is to start a brand new MMS thread, and you can’t stop people from chatting on the old threads.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing your baby monitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/securing-your-baby-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/securing-your-baby-monitor/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Ensuring that (only) you have secure remote access to your home IP camera It’s something every parent with a baby monitor fears. There have been multiple cases where people have had their monitoring devices “hacked” by strangers. There’s this story where a couple found a stranger talking to their 3 year old through the camera in his room. Here’s seven more examples of it happening in a BuzzFeed story.
Yikes! What can you do?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZFS on Linux vs Windows Storage Spaces with ReFS</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/zfs-on-linux-vs-windows-storage-spaces-with-refs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 05:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/zfs-on-linux-vs-windows-storage-spaces-with-refs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Choosing the right file system for your server Did you know that over time, your saved files can change and become corrupt, with absolutely no interaction on your part? All of our current storage mediums are susceptible; hard drive bits can lose their magnetic orientation and bits stored on solid state drives can slowly lose their electric charge. It’s commonly referred to as data decay, and Xkcd actually has a comic that jokes about the phenomenon offhandedly:
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get a Kindle Paperwhite for super cheap</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/get-a-kindle-paperwhite-for-super-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 16:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/get-a-kindle-paperwhite-for-super-cheap/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Black Friday or not Several years ago I got a Nook Simple Touch. I love the e-ink screen and the simplicity of a device focused solely on reading. No disruptive notifications or games, just books.
Although the screen was nice, I always felt like the ecosystem was lacking. I own a lot of books on Kindle, and the Kindle app no longer works on the dated Nook simple touch. I’ve also often wished the Nook had a built in light for the screen, for night reading.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling automated storage health checks</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/scheduling-automated-storage-health-checks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 05:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/scheduling-automated-storage-health-checks/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          and emailing yourself the results Most modern storage mediums (hard drives and solid state drives) have something call S.M.A.R.T. monitoring (Self-Monitoring, Analysis and Reporting Technology). Basically disks have built in monitoring systems that detect errors and can frequently predict drive failure before any data loss has occurred. This built in monitoring can be much more useful if you leverage it at the operating system level. I’m going to show you how you can schedule drive tests and configure them to send you updates to your personal email.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling automated ZFS scrubs</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/scheduling-automated-zfs-scrubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 04:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/scheduling-automated-zfs-scrubs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          and emailing yourself the results One of the big benefits to using ZFS is its ability to repair silent data corruption. There are two ways it can do this.
 When it reads data from disk, it will check the data against its stored checksum. If the data doesn’t pass this check, it will pull the same data from the other disk in a mirror configuration or from the rest of the disk array.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Sublime Text to be awesome</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/configuring-sublime-text-to-be-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/configuring-sublime-text-to-be-awesome/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Your text editor could look like this.
Sublime Text 3 is without a doubt my favorite text editor. It has a super flexible plugin API, and people have done some pretty amazing things with it. It has a much smaller footprint than an IDE like NetBeans/Eclipse/IntelliJ. It offers a lot of power with multi-cursor operations and bulk text editing. This post details some of my favorite plugins and the settings I prefer to use with Sublime.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why my blog is on Medium</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/why-my-blog-is-on-medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 05:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/why-my-blog-is-on-medium/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Instead of WordPress, Ghost, or Github Pages The Ghost blogging platform got its initial start on kickstarter. When I first read about it, it sounded perfect! Fully open source with a clean, simple, intuitive interface. None of the useless clutter that has overtaken that bloated pig Wordpress! I was already familiar with node and nginx, so I went ahead and spun up my own instance. It was beautiful! The side by side markdown editing was clean and intuitive.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 19:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/about/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          I love spending time with my family. I love building things (whether with power tools or with text editors) and I enjoy messing around with Linux VMs on my home server.
History Software Engineer, Qualtrics (May 2013-present)  I lead development on internal software.  Open source work  Made a chrome extension to send bulk texts via google voice Made a progressive web app to time your speed with math problems Added project-wide search to Caret  Software Engineering Intern, Sewell Direct (May 2012 — May 2013)  Built a unified search engine for internal use that searched orders, customers, suppliers, and more Built a client facing order tracking system where none existed before.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steam In-Home Streaming on a Chromebook</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/steam-inhome-streaming-on-a-chromebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 05:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/steam-inhome-streaming-on-a-chromebook/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Yes, it is possible. And it works great! I’ve been doing this for a while and it’s worked great for me, so I thought I’d share my learnings.
Note that this guide will only work on chromebooks with Intel processors.
Step 1: Install Ubuntu using Crouton First off, you’ll want to install Ubuntu on your chromebook using Crouton. The steps for doing that have already been covered on many blogs, so I won’t go into details there.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing ADB on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/installing-adb-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/installing-adb-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Instructions for both brew and manual installation (Updated April 25, 2017)
ADB stands for Android Debug Bridge. ADB is the officially provided way of interacting with android devices via terminal from desktops and laptops.
Note: Any code blocks like this one
should be executed inside the OS X terminal app.
Option 1 — Install it using Homebrew This is the easiest way and will provide automatic updates. Homebrew is a package manager for OS X, similar to apt-get for Ubuntu or yum for Fedora/CentOS.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caret vs Zed</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/caret-vs-zed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 04:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/caret-vs-zed/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Chrome text editor showdown Recently I’ve been looking for a decent text editor for Chromebooks. For work I mostly use Sublime text editor on OS X. In the past I’ve installed Ubuntu on my Chromebooks, either with Crouton or Chrubuntu. After getting an Asus C201 recently I wanted to see what native options there were for ChromeOS, as I intend to mostly just use it for hobby coding and blogging.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing code remotely with SSHFS</title>
      <link>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/writing-code-remotely-with-sshfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 19:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brismuth.com/posts/writing-code-remotely-with-sshfs/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Where I work, each developer has their own virtual machine that is only available inside our corporate network. Each developer has all their code on their laptops, and it is shared with their VM using NFS. This works great while inside the office, but sometimes we need to work from home.
The way our VPN is currently configured, our laptops do not keep the same internal IP address as they have when they are physically on the office network.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>